<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Blog for Ben</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Blog for Ben</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:42:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Relational Data and Drizzle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-03-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 14:42:21 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-03-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, remember this post&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auth with Drizzle, NestJS, and Passport</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mar_10_2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 13:23:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mar_10_2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a fairly large section, highlighting the process by which I&amp;rsquo;ve created the starting point for the auth and user registration for the new iteration of my bootcamp final project. I wanted to do my best to follow current best practices and build out a solid starting point for user registration and authentication. A primary reference for this work was this excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/S8Cjx5ua2JU?si=YAPZ5HOr6JTBTEMB&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@mguay&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Michael Guay&lt;/a&gt;. I like how he organizes the NestJS project and his approach seems to follow pretty solid, modern best practices, though these things seem to change all the time. He utilizes MongoDB/mongoose and not Postgres/Drizzle so for my app I had to do a fair bit of customization; couldn&amp;rsquo;t just use his code line by line. I&amp;rsquo;ll outline what I did in this article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Project: Picking my Backend</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pickingbackend/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 14:09:56 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pickingbackend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’ll talk about the first step I’ve taken towards my new pet project: a total rebuild of my bootcamp final project. My team of 3 completed this project in the span of 2 weeks at the very beginning of the 2020 pandemic… as in, we had been going to classes in person, then we entered quarantine just as we got our team assignments and completed everything remotely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the time we had only been writing code for 10 weeks. In our toolkit we had only vanilla JS + HTML + CSS for frontend, and Django and Python (notably no SQL) for backend. Our team bravely took on learning parts of Vue.js to help us build our UI. The backend was also a departure from what we knew. We used the Django REST framework so we could fetch our data instead of using the out of box Model-View-Template structure to pass data to our views.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ref Shenanigans Kicked my Butt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/useimperativehandle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 16:34:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/useimperativehandle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/useImperativeHandleDemo/shenanigans.png&#34; alt=&#34;shenanigans&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We all know you&amp;rsquo;re not actually supposed to try to use refs in a React app. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about when you need to save a mutable value without causing rerenders&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m referring to the &amp;ldquo;funny business&amp;rdquo; like attaching a ref to a DOM node or using it to lift up the API of a component. This kind of thing feels weird if you&amp;rsquo;re thinking in the &amp;ldquo;React Way&amp;rdquo;. It almost feels naughty&amp;ndash; hence, &amp;ldquo;shenanigans&amp;rdquo; &amp;#x1f602;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shower Thought</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/25feb23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 13:48:45 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/25feb23/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working on my new creative project and reminding myself how to use Next.js (I haven&amp;rsquo;t touched it since before my last job). This is a cool framework. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if they&amp;rsquo;ve just sold me on snake oil but if it works how it should, I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to use it and talk about it here!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Made a Blog, Not a Portfolio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/myfirstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:18:44 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/myfirstpost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#39;gradient-keyboard&#39;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a dev like me, a portfolio doesn&amp;rsquo;t do the job of illuminating my value and could be a waste of time. Creating a blog with Hugo allows me to save time in development. A blog provides a medium through which I can share what I know and what I&amp;rsquo;m doing in smaller, bite sized chunks. I can also keep a track record while I am also working on private projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
